Shahidul Islam

JUNIOR FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Email: shahid.okay@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/shahidul-islam401
GitHub: https://github.com/shahid129

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a soon to be graduate in Full-stack Software Development with a BA (Hons) in Marketing. I am seeking an opportunity to use my education and skillset to expand my knowledge, to help and contribute to your company's growth. I will be receiving my diploma from the Code Institute. I am proficient in HTML, CSS, Javascript, and Python. I have 5 years of experience in management, customer service and hospitality. I am a valuable team player with strong communication skills and significant problem-solving abilities.

KEY SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python.

• **Libraries:** Pytest

• Version Control: Heroku, GitHub, Git

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Feb 2022 – Feb 2023 Code Institute

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development (E-Commerce) Credit Rated by The University of the West of Scotland

Jan 2014 – Jun 2015 Anglia Ruskin University

Hons in Marketing

PORTFOLIO PROJECTS

1. Sully's Kitchen - A Fine Dining Restaurant.

GitHub - https://github.com/shahid129/sully-s-kitchen

Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS.

2. World of Game - Guess The Number game.

GitHub - https://github.com/shahid129/world-of-game

Technologies Used - HTML5 , CSS, JavaScript...

3. My-Sub My-Way - Sandwich Order System

GitHub - https://github.com/shahid129/my-sub-my-way

Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Google API, Heroku.

COLLABORATIVE PROJECTS

1. Hackathon - World Day - Organised by Code Institute.

This was a group project, over a 5 day period. We created a fully functioning site.

GitHub - https://github.com/RvN-R/the-planeteers

Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jun 2018 – Present Subway, Letterkenny, F92 P2OV Store Manager

- Managed a team of staff.
- Organised rosters taking staff availability into account.
- Stock management and ordering.
- Weekly banking and cash management.

Nov 2015 – May 2018 Lan Tania Restaurant, Maynooth, Ireland Assistant Chef

- In depth understanding of health and safety with HAACP certification.
- Details oriented in a fast paced working environment.
- Assist with the preparation and planning of meal design.
- Monitor and record inventory, and if necessary order new supplies.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Currently learning API, Bootstrap, Jquery, Flask, Django, Jest
- Languages: Fluent English/Fluent Bangla/Beginner Hindi,
- Member of Clondalkin Cricket Club.

INTERESTS

- Graphic Design learning Adobe Photoshop I enjoy creating and designing.
- Experimenting with codes both fronend and backend.
- Photography